i spring fans welcome to another
我春天的粉丝们欢迎来到另一个
installment of spring tips as always I'm
一如既往的春天技巧分期付款
happy to join you today I I'm excited
很高兴今天能加入你们，我很激动
about today's topic actually if I'm
关于今天的话题，如果我是
honest we're going to talk about Kotlin
老实说，我们将谈论科特林
and in particular we're gonna revisit
特别是我们要重温
Coughlin we've already talked about
我们已经谈论过的Coughlin
Coughlin a number of times on this this
Coughlin对此多次
humble screencast of ours but we're
我们的简明截屏，但我们
gonna focus in particular on co-routines
将特别关注协同例程
now the reason I've waited this long to
现在我等了这么久的原因
talk about it is because I wanted to get
谈论它是因为我想得到
it right and things were kind of in flux
没错，事情在不断变化
if you will when I looked at it a few
如果你愿意，当我看着它的时候
times and finally finally finally Kotlin
次，最后终于终于科特林
1.3 has been released and with it the
1.3已经发布，
core support for Kotlin itself has been
对Kotlin本身的核心支持是
made sort of generally available now
现在已经可以普遍使用了
there are some other things that are not
还有一些其他的东西不是
quite generally generally available and
相当普遍
you're gonna see that I'm gonna pull in
你会看到我要拉
some pieces that are not yet final but
有些作品还不是最终的，但是
they're relatively stable and people are
他们相对稳定，人们
using them and it's a great effect and
使用它们，效果很好，
you'll find and you know even even one
你会发现，你甚至知道一个
particularly nice aspect of the of that
特别好的方面
stability is that when I was looking for
稳定性是当我寻找
you know ideas or documentation and
您知道想法或文档，并且
things like that on it i found answers
像这样的事情我找到了答案
that were fairly applicable right most
最合适的权利
of the time is applicable so this tells
时间是适用的，所以这告诉
me that um it has remained stable long
我，嗯，它长期保持稳定
enough for their corpus of work talking
足以让他们的工作语录
about it and that's to the credit of the
关于它，这是值得赞扬的
team working on Kotlin itself for those
那些为Kotlin本身工作的团队
of you who listen to my little podcast
听我的小播客的你们中
and bootiful podcast available of course
和引导性播客当然可用
on all pot world we know on all
在所有锅底世界上，我们都知道
platforms where podcasts are downloaded
下载播客的平台
available through all popular podcasts
可通过所有流行的播客获得
including Apple iTunes I sorry yeah I
包括Apple iTunes，对不起，我
guess design tunes Google Play and of
猜测设计调整了Google Play和
course Spotify for those of you who
为您中的那些人提供Spotify课程
listen to that I even had the privilege
听我什至有幸
of interviewing the common teams Roman
采访罗马共同队
lazerov a few weeks ago and that
几周前的拉泽罗夫
interview was absolutely fascinating so
面试绝对让人着迷
if you want a lot more back sort of
如果你想要更多的回头
background on what we're gonna talk
我们要谈论的背景
about today if we run a lot more detail
关于今天，如果我们运行更多细节
we're gonna talk about today then you
我们今天要谈的就是你
should absolutely a since that podcast
绝对应该是那个播客
and while you're at it please subscribe
而当你在它，请订阅
but but we're gonna see what that looks
但我们要去看看
like what that translates into as we
就像转化为我们的东西一样
build an application today using Kotlin
今天使用Kotlin构建应用程序
wouldn't use the latest and greatest
不会使用最新的和最大的
spring boot up to
spring boot
3em3 whether we're just gonna call this
3em3我们是否要称呼它
code teens alright haha so they did
编码青少年好哈哈，所以他们做到了
their I swap the K for a C so you know
他们将K换成C，所以你知道
that's cool so we're these reactive web
太酷了，我们就是这些反应灵敏的网站
support we use a reactive MongoDB
支持我们使用反应式MongoDB
support we're gonna use I guess that's
支持我们将使用我猜那是
it okay I guess that's it that's most of
好的，我想就是这样
what we're gonna need that I can get
我们需要什么我可以得到
from the initializer um we can use
从初始化器um我们可以使用
MongoDB yeah we can use my going to be
是的，我们可以使用MongoDB
the nice thing is we can also use our -
不错的是，我们还可以使用-
DBC and I think we will do that as well
DBC，我想我们也会做
but keep in mind you don't have to um
但请记住，您不必
this isn't first well there's no
这不是一开始就没有
checkbox here but there is as we saw in
此处的复选框，但正如我们所见
a previous video experimental support
先前的视频实验支持
spread experiments Auto configuration
传播实验自动配置
support for that so maybe we'll get to
支持这一点，所以也许我们会去
it we'll see if I can I don't know
我们看看我是否能知道
either way know that you can and most of
无论哪种方式，您都可以知道
what you're gonna see today also applies
您今天要看到的内容也适用
there obviously there's a different
显然有不同的地方
domain model and different data type but
域模型和不同的数据类型，但是
um the the extension functions that
扩展功能
we're going to introduce that are
我们将介绍的是
applicable to MongoDB are similarly
适用于MongoDB的情况类似
applicable to our - DBC okay so we're
适用于我们的-DBC好的，所以我们
gonna hit generate I gotta give us a new
我要给我们一个新的
project and I'll open this up and by the
项目，我将打开它，并在
way can we take a moment to appreciate
我们可以花点时间欣赏的方式
just how amazing this brand new snazzy
这个崭新的时髦真令人赞叹
react based um spring initializer is
基于反应的um spring初始化器是
look at that that's you don't even know
看着那你甚至都不知道
where the code is right it's just it's
代码正确的地方就是
just all you know really nice-looking
只是你所知道的真的很漂亮
react yes and stuff a little hard to to
反应是，有些东西很难
penetrate in terms of parsing it by hand
渗透到手工解析方面
by eye but uh awesome stuff are
用肉眼看，但是很棒的东西
happening there that's cool so it's
发生在那很酷，所以
really fast you know okay anyway here we
真的很快，你知道吗，反正我们
go open that up
去打开那个
all right and as soon as this is loaded
好吧，一旦加载
the first thing that we're gonna take a
我们要做的第一件事是
look at is bringing in the right
看看带来了正确的
dependencies to make this work okay so
依赖使这项工作正常
we'll close that out good
我们将其关闭
all righty come on
好吧加油
does this one already exist okay good
这个已经存在好吗
stuff so we're going to build an
东西，所以我们要建立一个
application here we go and before we get
应用程序在这里，我们去之前
too far down the line of course we have
当然太远了
to add the right dependencies and
添加正确的依赖关系并
configure the right things to make this
配置正确的东西来做到这一点
work so the first thing I want to do is
工作，所以我要做的第一件事是
pull the version of Kotlin make sure
拉Kotlin版本确保
that's a 1.3 doh something 3.1 is fine
那是1.3英里3.1很好
and then we want to specify a version
然后我们要指定一个版本
for the cotton coal routines library so
对于棉煤常规库
i'll call them x co routines this is
我称它们为x co例程，这是
sort of like an incubator library
有点像孵化器库
outside of the main support for common
主要支持之外的共同点
in in outside of the main support for
在主要支持之外
co-routines in common and by the way
共同例程和顺便说一句
that's by design one of the really
这是设计使然的
really well-designed aspects of support
精心设计的支持方面
for Kotlin co meetings is that it is
对于Kotlin合作会议，是
that um I think there's one keyword
那个我认为有一个关键字
suspend I think that's the only thing
暂停，我认为那是唯一的事情
that's that's unique everything else is
那是独一无二的，其他一切都是
designed as functions right and the
设计为正确的功能
model is actually flexible enough that
模型实际上足够灵活
you can use it as a sort of generator or
您可以将其用作生成器或
you can use it as a sort of a as a sort
您可以将其用作某种
of async/await on a c-sharp in 2012 and
于2012年在c-sharp上执行async / await和
so it's really nice that they were able
所以他们真的很高兴
to implant such a flexible foundational
植入如此灵活的基础
thing and then defer to third-party
事，然后服从第三方
libraries to plug in the gaps in
库来填补空白
whatever way they would see fit and that
他们认为合适的任何方式
really has come out nicely in this API
这个API确实表现不错
so we'll see that here we're gonna
所以我们会在这里看到
actually see that in the some in this
其实看到了一些
library so okay what do we got we got
图书馆好吧，我们得到了什么，我们得到了
dependency we want caught Lennox Cole
我们想要抓住的依赖Lennox Cole
routines cool routines really active
例程很酷的例程真的很活跃
Dirk
短剑
okay so you can see we've got an adapter
好的，所以您可以看到我们有一个适配器
for reactor okay I'll get back to that
对于反应堆好吧，我会回到那个问题上
in a second and the version of course is
一秒钟，当然版本是
a property so Kotler co-routines
一个属性，所以Kotler协同工作
version alright good stuff copy that and
版本好东西复制那个和
we've got coupling code change version
我们有耦合代码更改版本
four core right here we are as well good
四个核心在这里，我们也很好
stuff okay so we've got the core bits
东西还好，所以我们有核心要素
there um I guess we need to argue or to
嗯，我想我们需要争论或
ABC I'll I'll just bring them in and
ABC，我将它们带入
well maybe use them maybe we won't you
好吧也许用他们也许我们不会
know I'm saying
知道我在说
copy add that in we need their
复制添加，我们需要他们
dependency management section down there
那里的依赖管理部分
okay I want to connect to my trusty
好吧，我想连接到我的信任
Costco's database they're good and we
Costco的数据库很好，我们
need to you know I think I'll do it with
需要知道我想
our TBC you'll get rid of MongoDB
我们的TBC，您将摆脱MongoDB
because I just like our to be C so much
因为我非常喜欢我们成为C
okay good stuff and now in our code well
好东西，现在在我们的代码中
when you visit all the stuff in a minute
一分钟内访问所有东西
but in our code let's comment out spring
但是在我们的代码中，让我们注释掉春季
boot for the moment and we're gonna
暂时启动，我们要
focus on first of all let's see if we
首先，让我们看看我们是否
can get the basic code working okay so
可以使基本代码正常工作
I'm gonna create a function or two
我要创建一个或两个函数
that'll help us in our work here we're
这将有助于我们在这里的工作
gonna comment this out and create a
将其注释掉并创建一个
function here that a log data to we're
这里的功能是向我们发送日志数据
gonna create a function that along stuff
会创建一个随东西而变的函数
out and we need to record the current
出来，我们需要记录当前
thread name and well record a message if
线程名称，如果有则记录一条消息
it's given to us and there we go now
它给了我们，我们现在就去
that'll be useful and then we'll also
这将是有用的，然后我们还将
record the current time right so instant
马上记录当前时间
dot now alright
点现在好了
and there we go so now we've got a thing
然后我们走了，所以现在我们有了一个东西
we can use to take notes and I'm just
我们可以用来做笔记，我只是
it's just a function it's just a public
这只是一个功能，只是一个公众
static void main continent program
静态无效主大陆程序
irregardless you know of spring or
不管你知道春天还是
anything like that and we can explore
这样的事情，我们可以探索
the ideas behind code routines okay
代码例程背后的想法还可以
that's when it when our focus on nice
当我们专注于美好的时候
thing in wind out three look at that
风中的东西三看那
don't even meet this anymore kind of
甚至不再遇到这种
cool I'm a fan um let's see do we have
酷，我是粉丝，让我们看看我们有
the we're gonna be using a preview
我们将使用预览
version of flow from Colin Cowie teams
Colin Cowie团队的流程版本
and this annotation tells intelligence
这个注解告诉你情报
to leave us alone
离开我们一个人
when we you know to to not bother us
当我们知道不要打扰我们时
with this reminder that it's a
提醒您，这是一个
experimental right very convenient and
实验权非常方便，
we're gonna need to we're gonna
我们将需要我们将
experiment with cortines now co-routines
现在试验皮质类药物
to its list let's round what we're doing
到清单上，让我们四舍五入
here in some background first all Co
首先在某些背景下
teams are a way to approach asynchronous
团队是一种异步方法
programming okay they are a way to move
编程好吧，它们是一种移动方式
work off of the current thread now
现在处理当前线程
there's a lot of ways to do that right a
有很多方法可以做到这一点
lot of ways to do that but you can
很多方法可以做到这一点，但是你可以
create a thread yourself and move that
自己创建一个线程并移动它
work into the background you can use
可以在后台使用
deferred or you know you no promises
推迟，或者你知道你没有承诺
api's or computable futures things like
api或可计算的期货之类的东西
that that certainly works as well the
那当然也很好
problem with this and you can even use
这个问题，你甚至可以使用
reactive types nice and I quite like
反应类型不错，我很喜欢
reactive types obviously you see me
反应型显然你看到我
talking about that quite a bit
谈论很多
those types are we're gonna actually use
这些类型是我们实际使用的
those reactive types but we're gonna use
这些反应类型，但我们要使用
them through this coaching API what the
他们通过此教练API可以
co-routines do is they give us a way to
例程是他们给我们一种方法
tell the language hey here's a thing
告诉语言，嘿，这件事
that I want to run asynchronously but I
我想异步运行，但我
want to resume execution of code as
想要恢复执行代码为
though I was running it synchronously
虽然我正在同步运行
and the way this works is that when you
运作的方式是当你
create a function let's say you know do
创建一个函数，假设您知道
something async like this okay this
像这样的东西异步
isn't this is not a coaching this is not
这不是教练吗？
a suspender Bowl thing when you do this
执行此操作时出现的吊带碗
and then you say okay
然后你说好
Wow a equals one and then you say um
哇等于1然后你说嗯
return string you know whatever
返回字符串你知道
I'm just getting a dummy thing like that
我只是得到像这样的假东西
okay um hello you say Val message equals
好的，你好，你说Val消息等于
do is something async and then you say
做的是异步的，然后你说
Val be equals to if you were to run this
如果您要运行此值，则等于
code nothing would be something would be
代码什么都不会是
special about this but you can run this
特别的，但是你可以运行这个
well you don't need to in this case you
好吧，在这种情况下您不需要
can run this on a separate thread and of
可以在单独的线程上运行
course what I want to happen here is you
当然我想在这里发生的是你
know Hello whatever parameter what I
知道你好，我什么参数
want to happen is that we get to this
想要发生的是，我们做到了
line in the code then we get to this
代码中的一行，然后我们进入
line and then this code this this main
行，然后此代码将此主要
method you know for all intents and
您知道的所有方法
purposes it stops here all right what
目的就止于此
happens is execution moves over to this
发生是执行移至此
date do async something just something
日期做一些异步的事情
async function and the state the sort of
异步功能和状态
the things that we have to do out here
我们在这里要做的事情
after here print line all that stuff you
在这里打印所有东西之后
know print line blah you know all that
知道打印线等等，你知道的一切
stuff gets wrapped up in a lambda right
东西被包裹在lambda中了
like this Val callback okay fun like
像这样的Val回调还可以吧
that right and this callback gets passed
正确的权限，此回调被传递
in to this function
进入这个功能
so really it's like this the compiler
所以真的就是这样的编译器
hopes us out by writing this code for us
希望我们通过为我们编写这段代码来
it passes in the callback and then it
它传入回调，然后
then after the function has finished it
然后在函数完成之后
makes sure that that we have you know
确保我们知道
write a string string right it makes
写一个正确的字符串
sure that after we're done with the
确保在我们完成后
business logic here where that whatever
这里的业务逻辑
we're trying to do that something calls
我们正在努力做到这一点
the callback and allows it to complete
回调并允许它完成
after this line and so the effect is
在这条线之后，所以效果是
that not the I'm sorry
那不是我很抱歉
you know the effect of that is that it
你知道那的效果是
looks to our from our perspective as
从我们的角度来看我们
something that's running on written in
正在写的东西
this way it looks like this executed
这样看起来像这样执行
then the I do something async happened
然后我做了一些异步的事情
and then and only then Val V equals two
然后只有Val V等于2
and print line happened it happens in
和打印行发生在
that order but what is actually
该命令，但实际上是什么
happening is that there's this fancy
发生的是有这种幻想
state that's being passed into the
状态被传递到
function and it's being kept for after
功能，并在以后保留
the business like logic is done it's
像逻辑这样的业务就完成了
been called and then you know looks like
被叫，然后你知道看起来像
it returned back to where you started so
它回到了你开始的地方
you had three lines before in the order
你之前有三行
in the order that you have it there it's
按照你在那里的顺序
still very much feels like three lines
还是很像三行
feels like you've got a some logic here
感觉这里有些逻辑
and then be right and B is the thing
然后说对了，B就是这个
that happens afterwards that's awesome
那会发生的，那很棒
right and that that state here I'm using
对的，我正在使用的那个状态
a lambda to kind of demonstrate the idea
一个lambda来证明这个想法
here but that's called a continuation
在这里，但这被称为延续
right it's actually an object that gets
对，实际上是一个物体
inserted for you by the compiler when it
当编译器为您插入
sees that you've got functionality that
看到您具有的功能
should be suspended
应该暂停
now this isn't suspended what I've just
现在这并没有暂停我刚刚
shown you here isn't actually suspended
告诉你这里实际上并没有暂停
in order for you to tell the compiler
为了告诉编译器
that something is suspended first of all
首先要暂停
you have to mark it with suspend all
你必须用全部暂停标记
right that's a fancy cube now you can
对，这是一个漂亮的立方体，现在您可以
see that there's nothing here the you
看到这里没有什么你
can see that this isn't special right I
可以看出这不是特别的权利
actually I haven't actually done
其实我还没做
anything that's suspended with yet and
暂停的任何东西，以及
the reason is because if I were to run
原因是因为如果我要跑步
something that is a time intensive right
耗时的权利
in this code it would sit there and
在这段代码中，它会坐在那里
block it would sit there just like
挡住它就像坐在那里
anything else if I tried to do thread
还有其他如果我尝试做线程
dot sleep for example well you can see
例如点睡眠，你可以看到
the tool would tell me oh that's not
该工具会告诉我哦，那不是
good it's inappropriate use and also I'm
很好，使用不当，我也是
returning there it's inappropriate use
返回那里是不适当的使用
of a blocking API but really the result
API的作用，但实际上是结果
would be the same you would if you were
如果你曾经是
to call this code like this even though
即使这样也可以调用此代码
it's mark to suspend this would block
这是暂停的标记
right what you would have to do is to
对，您要做的就是
use with context right sorry context is
与上下文一起使用对不起，上下文是
it
它
which with context you have to use
您必须使用上下文
something I have to get the name of the
我必须得到一些东西的名字
API and it isn't all that much matter I
API并没有那么重要
don't really want to get too much into
真的不想投入太多
that but you have to use something to
那，但是你必须使用一些东西
teach the runtime how to make this thing
教运行时如何做这件事
asynchronous right how do you how do you
异步对，你怎么样
how do you figure out when how do you
你如何弄清楚你什么时候
how do you figure out how to start it
你如何弄清楚如何开始
and how do you figure out what it looks
以及你如何看待它的外观
like when it's done and that's I think
就像完成时那样，我认为
it's called with context or something
它被称为上下文或其他
like that the result is that you're
这样的结果是你
actually teaching you're actually
实际上教你
teaching the runtime how to make this
教运行时如何做到这一点
thing that is blocking you're teaching
阻碍你教学的东西
it what part you can launch in the
它可以在哪个部分启动
background and what it looks like when
背景以及什么时候
it's done and then it can just shoot
完成后就可以拍摄了
that as an asynchronous thing right and
作为异步事物，
you can also move that on to a thread
您也可以将其移至线程
basically you're moving it onto a
基本上，您将其移动到
schedule so that that with context thing
安排时间，以便与上下文相关的事物
does that for you right so most of the
这样做对您来说是正确的，所以大多数
time you won't have to worry about that
时间，您不必担心
you won't have to hopefully most of the
您将不必希望大部分
time you're not gonna be worrying about
时间你不用担心
how to make things that are synchronous
如何使事物同步
feel asynchronous through this adapter
通过此适配器感到异步
code what is important to understand is
代码重要的是要理解的是
that there are a lot of functions a lot
有很多功能
of API calls that you can make in Kotlin
您可以在Kotlin中进行的API调用的数量
proper in Kotlin X and in spring in
在Kotlin X和春季在
general that already support this and do
将军已经支持并执行
this for you
这个给你
so reactor code reactive code that uses
所以反应堆代码使用
publishers that uses these things that
使用这些东西的发布者
are that you can start and then you that
是你可以开始，然后你那个
have an own way to finish you know you
有自己的方式来完成你认识你
can you can subscribe and get the result
您可以订阅并获得结果吗
and they emit items we can we can
他们发射出我们可以的物品
generically adapt a publisher into
通常使发布者适应
something that looks like a suspender
看起来像吊带的东西
function for common and so we've done
通用功能，所以我们完成了
that for you automatically write in a
为您自动写入
lot of different places throughout this
整个过程中有很多不同的地方
Bing sort of ecosystem now this is
必应这样的生态系统
support a lot of it originally debuted
支持很多它最初首次亮相
in spring foo our micro framework I did
在春季foo，我做了微框架
a spring tip video on that a while back
一会儿的春天提示视频
as well spring foo looks at a number of
以及春季foo看了很多
these different api's and I don't I'm
这些不同的api，而我不是
not sure if we even interest Cortines
不知道我们是否甚至对Cortines感兴趣
there but the point is it's super easy
在那里，但关键是它非常容易
to do with covert teams so now that you
与秘密团队合作，现在你
kind of understand the idea that you've
有点了解你的想法
got this suspended keyword that you can
得到了这个可以暂停的关键字
use for functions that intern also
用于也可以进行实习的功能
all things that are non-blocking you
所有阻止你的事情
know now you've got I think I hope
知道现在你有我想我希望
you've got an idea for what's possible
你对可能的想法
now let's look at what that looks like
现在让我们来看一下
in practice let's write some basic
在实践中，让我们写一些基本的
co-routine code to get an idea for what
协同程序代码以了解什么
it is let's say I want to launch some
假设我要启动一些
asynchronous behavior okay so I'm gonna
异步行为好，所以我要
note let's do actual create a bunch of
注意，让我们实际创建一堆
functions one here and I'll say one okay
在这里功能一个，我会说一个好
and I'll say mmm I want to delay you
我会说mmm我想耽误你
want to call today this is a
今天想打电话给我
non-blocking thread sleep okay
非阻塞线程睡眠好
so I'll say I want to sleep for one
所以我要睡一个
second okay but in order to call that
第二可以，但是为了打电话
this is the compiler error saying hey
这是编译器错误，说嘿
you can't do that you need to call it
你做不到，你需要调用它
from a KO routine or another suspending
从KO例行程序或其他暂停中
okay so I'm gonna do that within the
好吧，我要在
context of a protein I'll say global
我要说的是蛋白质的整体背景
scope dot bunch and then with that so
范围点束，然后这样
now I've called lunch if you look at the
现在我叫午餐，如果你看
documentation for lunch
午餐文件
this only launched it just launches a
这只是发射它只是发射一个
new Co routine without blocking the
新的Co例程而不会阻塞
current thread and it returns a
当前线程，它返回一个
reference as a job okay so I'm actually
参考作为工作好吧，所以我实际上
Val job why can't I take the job
Val工作为什么我不能工作
okay now I can say it canceled right I
好吧，现在我可以说它取消了
can cancel if I want I can cancel and
可以取消，如果我想取消
join I can cancel that children like the
加入吧，我可以取消像
other code teens inside of it I can do
我可以做的其他代码青少年
all sorts of things here if I want in
如果我想在这里各种各样的事情
which case it will stop so that's kind
在哪种情况下它会停止，所以
of interesting isn't it you've got now a
有趣的是，现在您已经
way to sort of stop a you asynchronous
停止异步的方式
thing as it is though it'll already do
事情虽然已经完成了
something interesting so let's see what
一些有趣的东西，让我们看看
this is all right I'm gonna note the end
没关系，我要结束
of one okay I'm gonna note the results
好的，我要记录一下结果
and then I'll note that I'm gonna start
然后我会注意到我要开始
here okay so let's see what that looks
好的，让我们看看它的外观
like
喜欢
okay um I do something start you
好的，我开始做某事
shouldn't need to do that though oh you
哦，你不需要这么做
know what happened I know what happened
知道发生了什么我知道发生了什么
it's asynchronous it's obvious so I'm
这是异步的，很明显，所以我
gonna make the program as a general
将使程序成为一般
thing no matter what examples I do on
不管我做什么事
them asleep for 10 seconds that's so
他们睡了十秒钟
that so that it doesn't kill the the
这样就不会杀死
process before any eight asynchronous
任何八个异步之前的进程
outstanding threads have had the chance
优秀的线程有机会
to running so we started at this time
开始运行，所以我们此时开始
okay seven o'clock
好，七点钟
three minutes 15 seconds alright and
三分十五秒
we're expecting it to sleep oh I
我们期待它入睡哦，我
actually made it sleep for 10 seconds so
实际上让它睡了十秒钟，所以
it actually ran a little longer cuz we
它实际上跑了更长的时间，因为我们
only gave it to ten seconds in general I
一般只给了十秒钟
mean I should make this 20 just in case
我应该把这个设为20
I make that done that mistake again so
我再次犯了这个错误
there you go I can see it actually it
你去那里我可以看到它实际上
completed let's make up 20 you can see
完成，让我们组成20您可以看到
it completed in a different thread
它在另一个线程中完成
alright that's pretty straightforward
好吧，这很简单
right I mean I'm launching code in here
对，我的意思是我要在这里启动代码
and if I have something that is
如果我有一些东西
suspended I can launch it inside of this
暂停，我可以在其中启动它
as well okay so that's one what about
好的，那就是那一件事
let's look at another example
让我们看另一个例子
- okay I'm just gonna keep creating
-好的，我要继续创造
functions inside of functions because it
功能之内的功能，因为它
scotland it's all something I can now
苏格兰，这就是我现在所能拥有的一切
what if I want to have you can see that
如果我想让你看到
in this case in number one this is
在这种情况下，这是第一
obviously asynchronous it's like a
显然是异步的，就像
thread it's like I created a new thread
线程就像我创建了一个新线程
and it stopped
它停止了
you know it finished after I started
你知道我开始后就完成了
Facebook but what if I want things to
Facebook，但是如果我想要事情怎么办
run linearly like I want to have ABC I
像我想要ABC一样线性运行
want to be able to say run this
希望能够说出这个
asynchronously and then run an ABC well
异步运行ABC
I can use run blocking and this is what
我可以使用运行阻止，这就是
I would use inside of main code this is
我会在主要代码中使用这是
a great way to adapt suspend of a code
适应代码暂停的好方法
to main code right you you'll probably
正确的主代码，您可能会
use this at the top level of your
在您的顶层使用此
application and then everything after
应用程序，然后一切
that is suspended function so here I'm
那是暂停功能，所以我在这里
gonna say note
要说笔记
to start okay note to stop and here what
开始好吧，请注意停止，然后在这里
I'm going to do in here I'm going to
我要在这里做
delay two seconds and on the note run
延迟两秒钟，然后运行音符
blocking let's heart to blocking end and
阻挡让我们全心全意阻挡终点，
start alright then we need to run to oh
开始好吧，那我们需要跑哦
I have to invoke it
我必须调用它
okay so to start blocking start blocking
好的，所以开始阻止开始阻止
end
结束
right so I'm inside the blocking end and
对，所以我在阻塞端
the today happened so I can see it says
今天发生了，所以我可以看到它说
29 blah blah and then 31 okay so I slept
29等等等等然后31好吧，我睡了
for two seconds and then it finished in
持续两秒钟，然后完成
this case things are linear linear all
这种情况下所有东西都是线性的
right then linear they actually proceed
然后线性，他们实际上会继续
as though we want them to right and
好像我们要他们纠正
that's good that's actually that gives
很好，实际上给了
you the ability to force things to
你有能力强迫事物
happen to sit in a certain sequence if
如果碰巧按一定顺序坐下
you're unsure about them now what about
你现在不确定他们呢
three what's the next example here fun
三个有趣的下一个例子是什么
three here we're gonna look at a sink
三个我们要看一个水槽
okay so let's say I have a bunch of
好吧，让我们说我有一堆
numbers and I want to sum them together
我想把它们加起来
okay and this is an example I got from
好的，这是我从中得到的一个例子
the documentation I think it's quite
我认为文档相当
illustrative so I'll do it for you okay
说明性的，我会为你做的
so it deferred equals one a million okay
所以递延等于一百万还可以
so I'm going to sum up each one I'm
所以我要总结我每个人
going to create a range this is a common
要创建一个范围，这是常见的
syntax for creating a range one to a
用于创建范围1到a的语法
million numbers okay and then I'm gonna
万个数字好，然后我要
map over each one and in Kotlin you
映射每个地图，在Kotlin中
specify a pram right like that or you
像这样指定一辆婴儿车
can just use the implicit variable each
可以只使用每个隐式变量
that's from including for example and so
这是因为包括例如
what I want to do is I want to return
我想做的就是我要回来
each item each number okay
每个项目每个数字都可以
I'm gonna sleep for a second so let me
我要睡一秒钟所以让我
just return them but before I do that
只是退还他们，但在我这样做之前
I'm gonna sleep for one second and of
我要睡一秒钟
course in order to sleep I need to I
当然要睡觉我需要我
need to run this code asynchronous oh
需要异步运行此代码哦
right so actually let's try this let's
对，所以实际上让我们尝试一下
try doing thread that sleep what
尝试做线程，睡觉什么
happened to you okay so if I do a thread
发生在你身上好吧，如果我做一个线程
at sleep
在睡觉
what is gonna happen I'm gonna I'm gonna
将会发生什么我要去
then go through this this range I'm
然后经过这个范围我
gonna say deferred dot some bye alright
要说推迟点再见
and I'm gonna say some bye
我要说再见
and it alright so the the result the
好吧，结果是
total sum is gonna be the sum of all
总和将是所有的总和
these numbers involved in the
这些数字涉及
I'm just gonna it's gonna be a self I'm
我只是要成为一个自我
just gonna say take it and add it right
只是说要接受并添加正确
I'm not gonna do thing else so it is
我不会做别的事情，所以
each number in the thing well what does
事情中的每个数字都很好
that mean what does it look like first
这意味着首先看起来像什么
of all that means it's gonna create a
所有这意味着它将创造一个
million numbers and each time it tends
百万数字，每次趋向
to sleep a second I don't have that kind
睡一秒钟我没有那种
of time I don't have a million seconds
时间我没有一百万秒
to wait for this result all right so I'm
等待这个结果好吧，所以我
not even gonna bother running this for
甚至都不会为这个而烦恼
you we can well we can run it for now we
您，我们可以，我们现在可以运行它
can try note after some we'll never get
可以尝试一些我们永远不会得到的笔记
there right before time okay
在时间之前就可以了
some okay so that's that's not a good
好吧，那不是一个好习惯
it's not gonna be a great result we're
这不是一个伟大的结果，我们
not gonna like what's happening here but
不喜欢这里发生的事情，但是
I'll let it run for a half a second or
我让它运行半秒钟或
two or five or whatever and if you can
两个或五个或任何东西，如果可以的话
maybe even hear my computer struggling
甚至听到我的电脑在挣扎
because it doesn't like what's just
因为它不喜欢什么
happened right okay yeah point made
发生了，好吧，是的
right so now what if I want to do this
对吧，现在如果我想这样做
what if I wanted to add a million
如果我想增加一百万怎么办
seconds a million things but I want to
一百万秒，但我想
do this asynchronous so that way I sleep
做这个异步，这样我睡觉
but I see without blocking the parent
但我看到没有阻止父母
thread in this case I can do global
在这种情况下，我可以全局
scope dot async and here I mean instead
范围点异步，这里我的意思是
of using thread out sleep which we
使用线程睡眠的
already established isn't appropriate my
已经建立不适合我
zone is a some whole thing I'll do that
我要做的就是整个区域
and I return no all right so now what
我没有返回好，现在呢
I've got now is a deferred the result of
我现在得到的是推迟的结果
calling async is a deferred of type T
调用异步是类型T的延迟
okay and so in order to get the value
好，这样才能获得价值
now now what I have it now what I have
现在，现在我所拥有的现在，现在我所拥有的
is a sequence of deferred and so for
是一个延迟序列，因此
each value I need to call a weight okay
我需要称重的每个值都可以
but of course in order to call a weight
但是当然是为了称重
I need to be inside of a code team all
我需要成为代码团队的一员
right cuz im using deferred I need to
正确的即时通讯使用延期我需要
also run this inside of a code team so
还要在代码团队内部运行
I'm gonna side I'm gonna say
我要站在一边我要说
run blocking so what does it happen now
运行阻止，所以现在发生了什么
I've got a deferred collection I'm
我有一个延期的收藏
visiting a million items and I'm gonna
参观一百万件物品，我要
create a million not threads right
创建一百万个不是线程的权利
lightweight fibers kind of you know not
轻质纤维那种你不知道
threads I certainly wouldn't want to
我当然不想的线程
create a million threads on this machine
在这台机器上创建一百万个线程
oh I need to call three I've got see if
哦，我需要打三个电话，看看
we can do that
我们能做到这一点
so
所以
good there's a result that's the number
好，结果就是数字
right if you take a million numbers and
正确，如果您使用一百万个数字
add them together you get that right and
将它们加在一起，您就正确了，
it didn't take very long at all it took
并没有花很长时间
10 20 to 24 so 2 2 seconds to move on to
10 20到24，所以2 2秒继续前进
a number of carrier threads on on the
上的许多载体线程
operating system on the on the JVM not a
JVM上的操作系统不是
million turns if you create a million
如果创造一百万个，则变成一百万个
ones
那些
it just very efficiently move to work on
它只是非常有效地继续工作
and off the threads so that I can do a
然后关闭线程，这样我就可以
million things as fast as possible right
尽快完成一百万件事
and because it had this this async
而且因为它有这个异步
coating here and because you know we use
涂料在这里，因为你知道我们使用
the non-blocking version of this as soon
此版本的非阻塞版本
as it's sleeping as soon as it slept I
睡一觉就睡着了
told the runtime hey I'm no longer using
告诉运行时，嘿，我不再使用
this thread somebody else can use it
这个线程可以被其他人使用
so while you know while one finally made
所以当你知道当一个人终于
it to a million and while one finally
到一百万，最后一个
made it to one second it got the thread
一秒钟就得到了线程
and was able to free itself up and
并能够释放自己，
Tamayo she was able to use it and so on
Tamayo她能够使用它，依此类推
so it just kept going like that as fast
所以它只是一直保持这样快
as possible this meant that all the
这意味着所有
computations just took two seconds
计算只花了两秒钟
that's very convenient
那很方便
ok now what about this one
好的，那这个呢
let's see right now I've shown you how
让我们现在看看我已经向您展示了
to use deferred and deferred is great
使用延期和延期很棒
for a single value data okay a single
对于单个值数据，可以单个
value of data that you want to return
您要返回的数据的值
it's kind of like up to a completable
有点像一个完整的
future but it works with coatings right
未来，但它适用于涂料
and you can see we're getting the same
你会看到我们也一样
benefits here of asynchronous
异步的好处
programming but we're not really dealing
编程，但我们并没有真正处理
with a lot of complexity how we're not
非常复杂，我们如何
doing countdown matches or cyclic
做倒计时比赛或循环
barriers or things as a semaphore or
障碍或诸如信号量之类的东西
whatever okay so now I'm gonna look at
好的，所以现在我要看看
another example here now we're going to
另一个例子，我们现在要
look at how do I solve the problem of
看看我该如何解决
having a lot of data right obviously a
拥有大量数据，显然是
very simple example would be to use
一个非常简单的例子就是
reactive code right you get a publisher
反应式代码就可以让您成为发布者
but publishers aren't by default aware
但默认情况下，发布商不知道
of co-routines they don't know how by
他们不知道如何通过共同例程
default - they don't they don't look
默认-他们不，他们看起来不
synchronous right there there there's
同步在那里
very clearly this sort of a sickness
很明显这种病
behavior there and so you can't write
那里的行为，所以你不能写
code that looks like a synchronous
看起来像同步的代码
blocking code so what I'm gonna do now
阻止代码，所以我现在要做什么
is I'm going to introduce a new type
我要介绍一种新型的
called a flow okay so here fun four and
叫做流程还行，所以这里很有趣，四个
here it'll be a four and I'll say that I
这将是四，我会说我
want to have a collection of integers a
想要有一个整数集合
flow events okay and this is another
流事件还可以，这是另一个
example I think I got from the
例如，我认为我从
documentation or from one of Roman and
文档或罗马和
these are off so amazing vlogs either
这些都关闭了，所以很棒的视频博客
way worth visiting and so a flow is kind
值得一游的方式，所以流程很亲切
of like a publisher but with code tips
像发布者一样，但具有代码提示
okay and so I'm gonna create a float I'm
好，所以我要创建一个浮动
going to create a flow and I'm going to
要创建一个流程，我要
emit values into this flow and I can do
向该流程中发送值，我可以做
this at whatever cadence I want very
无论我想要什么节奏
much like using flux crate and reactive
非常类似于使用助焊剂板条箱和反应堆
walls I'm creating a thing that will
墙我正在创造一个东西，
periodically emit value so I'm going to
定期散发价值，所以我要
say for I in 110 okay whoops
在110声中为我说声
all right and I'm gonna sleep a second
好吧，我要睡一会儿
between each one and then I'll omit an
在每个之间，然后我将省略
item and now I've got a flow that's got
项目，现在我有一个流程
it's gonna have a ten items and I'm
它要有十个项目，我是
gonna now iterate over that but of
现在要遍历，但是
course in order to do that I need to do
为了做到这一点，我需要做的
this and the adapter of glue layer here
这和这里的胶层适配器
and I'll say in start collect I'm gonna
我会说开始收集
log out the dope the data so note it
注销涂料数据，因此请注意
okay good stuff and we're gonna call for
好东西，我们将呼吁
okay so we're doing that we're actually
好的，所以我们正在这样做，实际上
visiting the data you know we're
访问您知道的数据
actually creating a flow that emits data
实际创建一个发出数据的流
periodically the nice thing about that
定期关于这件事的好处
is that even though it's taking time
即使需要时间
again we don't know what it we're not
再一次，我们不知道那不是什么
necessarily we're not sitting there on
一定我们不坐在那里
that thread wasting that thread so that
那个线程浪费了那个线程，所以
nobody else can use it we can get off
没有人可以使用它，我们可以下车
that thread right that's the benefit
那个线程权利就是好处
here in this case it's the main thread
在这种情况下，这是主线程
but imagine some other thread in the
但是想像一下
third pool you want to get off of that
您想摆脱的第三个泳池
in between the raindrops there in
在雨滴之间
between the emission of new data and so
之间的新数据的发射等
you want something else to be able to
你想要其他的东西能够
reuse that now you can do that because
现在可以重复使用，因为
delay doesn't block the client thread
延迟不会阻止客户端线程
the calling print okay five here I think
我认为这里的电话打印好五个
it's time for us to look at how this all
现在是时候让我们看看这一切
plays into spring okay so I want to do
玩到春天好吧，我想做
is though we're going to create some
虽然我们要创建一些
data right we're gonna quit some data
正确的数据，我们要退出一些数据
that will get launched in the normal way
将以正常方式启动
so we'll say well first of all five okay
所以我们先说五个好吧
and we're gonna create a data class call
我们将创建一个数据类调用
the reservation about ID int name string
关于ID int名称字符串的保留
okay oh wow name string and we want to
好的，哇，名字字符串，我们要
have a class reservation repository
有一个班级预订仓库
alrighty Wow
好吧哇
Davis quiet DBC all right and good stuff
戴维斯（Davis）安静的DBC不错，好东西
okay so now I'm gonna have a repository
好吧，现在我要有一个存储库
that's going to be using the r2 DC
那将使用r2 DC
Davies client I should make that private
Davies客户我应该将其设为私有
that's good
那很好
good practice there it's gonna be a
好的做法，它将有一个
thing that uses the database client and
使用数据库客户端和
now what I want to do is I want to use
现在我要使用的是
the Davis client to call into my sequel
戴维斯客户请我续集
data store I've got post graduate
我毕业的数据存储
writing the background we need to
编写我们需要的背景
configure a connection factory so I'm
配置一个连接工厂，所以我
gonna run my screen good application
将运行我的屏幕良好的应用程序
we're gonna provide some configuration
我们将提供一些配置
here about minutes okay and
在这里大约几分钟就可以了
okay let's see here will quit beans
好吧，让我们看看这里会退出豆子
using the DSL and Cottman for functional
使用DSL和Cottman实现功能
team definitions you don't have to use
您不必使用的团队定义
this you can use Java config or whatever
这你可以使用Java配置或任何
but I quite like it when in the cotton
但是当我穿棉布的时候我很喜欢
caught in the world so I'm gonna create
陷入世界，所以我要创造
a beam here for a connection factory
在这里连接工厂的光束
connection factories connection factory
连接工厂连接工厂
dot yet and I'm going to reference my
点了，我将参考我的
environment by spring ferric environment
春季铁水环境
and pull out the property here called
并拔出这里称为
spring dot are two DB c WR l and that
弹簧点是两个DB c WR l，
could be knowable so I need to force it
可能是众所周知的，所以我需要强制
to so we to realize that fact alright
所以我们意识到这个事实
and there you go that's my beam for the
然后你走了，那是我的光芒
connection factory for our TBC I need a
我们TBC的连接工厂，我需要一个
reservation repository we don't might
我们可能没有的预订库
still get that done right now and I'll
还是现在就完成，我会
just use ref again to tell it to inject
再次使用ref告诉它注入
a reference to another beam by type you
根据您的类型对另一个梁的引用
can way it can infer based on if I had
可以根据我是否有推断
ratified generics that the parameter to
批准的泛型参数
this is Davis client and so it can
这是戴维斯的客户，所以可以
actually capture that it's like being
实际捕捉到这就像是
able to capture generic type information
能够捕获通用类型信息
in Java which you can't really do but
在Java中，您实际上无法做到，但是
you can do it in common kind of right
你可以以共同的权利做到这一点
and then finally we're gonna create a
最后我们要创建一个
web endpoint we'll do that in a second
Web端点，我们将在一秒钟内完成
but let's get rid of that I'm gonna stay
但让我们摆脱的是，我要留下来
at initializers oh no we need actually
在初始化器中哦，不，我们实际上需要
run the application so I'll say run
运行应用程序，所以我会说运行
application and the application is of
应用程序和应用程序的
type Coughlin I start coatings okay and
Coughlin型我开始涂涂料好了
we need to create that main class again
我们需要再次创建该主类
so here we go
所以我们开始
cold routines application all right good
冷套路的应用还可以吧
stuff good stuff okay
好东西好吗
those beans there's a coatings
那些豆子有涂层
application and inside that we need to
应用程序以及我们需要的内部
add an it adder initializers and that's
添加一个it adder初始化程序，那就是
where we can pass in our beans
我们可以在其中传递豆子的地方
functional initializer you know
你知道的功能初始化器
functional mean registration in your
您的功能性均值注册
sizer and now with that done we can
大小调整器，现在完成了
build a repository that's the sports
建立一个体育运动的仓库
that supports you know common uses of
支持您知道
our of our database of our our TBC
我们的TBC数据库
database I'm going to say suspend fun
我要说的数据库暂停乐趣
find one okay and I'm going to say give
找到一个好的，我要说给
it a name spring and I want the results
春天来了，我想要结果
to be a reservation if possible now in
如果可能的话，现在保留
common reservations are they are
常见的保留意见是
knowable if you'd give them a question
知道是否要问他们一个问题
mark so I'm going to say that I want
标记，所以我要说我想要
this to be knowable and I'm gonna say I
这是众所周知的，我要说我
want to execute a query and I want to
想执行查询，而我想
find sequel I'll say select all from the
找到续集，我会说“全选”
reservation where name equals name
名称等于名称的保留
alright and when I'm binding the
好吧，当我绑定
parameter name to name and let's say as
以参数名称命名，假设为
type I want this to be I'm gonna use the
类型，我想要这个，我要使用
extension functions here right to
扩展功能在这里
capture that generic information and I'm
捕获那些通用信息，我就是
gonna fetch it now what that returns is
现在要获取它返回的是
a fetch spec and in the reactive world
提取规范和反应式世界
you just say all and that would be it
你只说全部而已
that would give you a publisher of
那会给你一个出版商
reservation okay but we're using the
保留好，但是我们正在使用
cotton API and we can actually use these
棉花API，我们实际上可以使用这些
extension functions including one or
扩展功能，包括一个或
null that will actually take this it'll
null，实际上将采取此措施
turn this into a thing that returns that
把它变成一个返回的东西
resolves into a value right but when
解析为价值权，但是当
somebody calls this function we're not
有人称我们不是
gonna sit there waiting for the value to
要坐在那里等待价值
me to realize it'll actually trigger the
我意识到这实际上会触发
suspension of the thread and
线程的暂停和
funny is available then we'll resume and
有趣，那么我们将继续，
I'll have the continuation right there's
我要继续下去
a continuation but I'll get past in here
延续，但我会过去
so whatever comes before this function
所以此功能之前的内容
whatever comes before the call into this
呼叫之前有什么
function well we'll pick up right after
运作良好，我们将在之后接载
it finishes just as though it finished
就像完成一样完成
on the same thread okay
在同一线程上好
let's find one and what about fun all
让我们找到一个有趣的东西
right all of it well here I'm not using
对，一切都很好，这里我没有用
anything I'm not gonna do what I'm gonna
我不会做的所有事情
do is I'm gonna convert it into a flow
我要做的就是将其转换为流
okay so what I want to do is I want to
好吧，所以我想做的是
get all the values from the database I'm
从数据库中获取所有值
going to say DB C dot select got from
会说DB C点选择来自
reservation dot as type and the type of
保留点的类型和类型
thing of course reservation and here I'm
当然要预约，我在这里
going to turn it into a flow so flow is
要把它变成流动，所以流动是
that thing I talked to you about before
我以前跟你说的那件事
that supports iterating or working with
支持迭代或使用
a stream of asynchronous values like a
异步值流，例如
publisher all right so that fetch that
出版商可以，以便获取
flow there's a extension function good
流程有一个扩展功能很好
stuff now we can use that right and what
现在我们可以使用该权限以及什么
I want to do is I want to use this
我想做的就是我要用这个
repository in building a REST API and
建立REST API和
again we have an opportunity if so I'm
如果有的话，我们再次有机会
gonna build a letter router and now you
要建造一个信路由器，现在你
might remember that when I showed you
可能记得当我向你展示时
this before there's actually a DSL you
在没有DSL之前，
can use for functional reactive HTTP
可以用于功能性反应式HTTP
endpoints and there's an even nicer DSL
端点，还有更好的DSL
in common well if you want to do cool
一般而言，如果你想做凉
routine based web applications instead
基于常规的Web应用程序
of reactive web applications you can do
您可以执行的反应式Web应用程序
that as well and the only thing that
那也是唯一的
switches up is let's say I create a
开关是假设我创建了一个
reference to this I get a reference to
对此我有参考
my reservation repository the only thing
我的预订库唯一
that switches up now is you use a coal
现在换的是你用煤
router and so to co-routine router
路由器等，以共同例程路由器
instead of a ringer router with that in
而不是带有的铃声路由器
place you say reservations server
你说预订服务器的地方
responds okay that body and we're not
那个身体反应很好，我们不是
gonna use body fluid body we need body
要使用体液，我们需要身体
flow okay and I'm in order to do that
没关系，我是为了做到这一点
I'm gonna say RR dot all cool
我要说RR点很酷
and I'll say I want to get a particular
我会说我想变得特别
one I'm by the way body flow and a
我顺便说一句，身体流动
weight is an asynchronous it's a it's a
重量是异步的，这是一个
not many singers it's an extension type
歌手不多，这是扩展类型
alright it's an extension function that
好吧，这是一个扩展功能
was added to this type that doesn't
被添加到这种类型的
exist there in the Java API all all
全部存在于Java API中
praise the power of the continent DSL
赞美大陆DSL的力量
for extensions okay
扩展好吗
then the body that we want to send back
然后我们要寄回的尸体
in this case is RR dot find one and the
在这种情况下，RR点找到一个，并且
name will be the request letter so it is
名称将是请求字母，因此
X is the request
X是请求
it's the request actually it there's one
这是要求，实际上有一个
parameter to call the request
调用请求的参数
it's a servlet it's a server request but
这是一个servlet，这是一个服务器请求，但是
I'm just gonna use the implicit
我只是要使用隐式
parameter called it I'm going to find
我将找到的参数称为
the data find its name and if that data
数据找到其名称，如果该数据
exists great if it doesn't I'll just
如果不是的话，那会很棒
throw a legal argument exception okay so
抛出法律论据异常好吧
the name is not valid good
名称无效
and then I'll send the response dot body
然后我将发送响应点正文
and a wait so now I'm just saying a
等一下，现在我只是说一个
single value I don't need the with the
我不需要的单个值
flow support there but they're both you
在那里提供支持，但他们都是你们
know their book powered by cogent with a
知道他们的书由cogent提供支持
name is super cool
名字太酷了
alrighty so what did I do wrong now or
好吧，那么我现在做错了什么呢？
is it not this there you go
这不是你去的地方吗
cool ok so now let's try this one more
很好，现在让我们再尝试一次
time instead of calling 5 I'm gonna call
时间，而不是打电话给我5
6 what is five yeah 5 to mind
6五是什么5介意
all righty so local host reservations
好的，所以本地主机保留
good stuff huh there's our data get one
好东西，有我们的数据
particular record that's working nice so
特别有效的记录，所以
we've just used co-routine support baked
我们刚刚使用了协同例程支持
into spring in compton we'd looked at I
进入康普顿的春天，我们看着我
mean you know I'm not interesting
意思是你知道我没意思
hopefully anything to new to all of you
希望对你们所有人都新鲜
we've looked at previous things we
我们已经看过以前的事情
looked at the functional reactive DSL in
看了功能性反应式DSL
Kotlin before we've looked at our 2d bc
Kotlin在我们看完2d BC之前
before right we looked at programmatic
在正确之前，我们着眼于程序化
billion registration from from
来自的十亿注册
registration before we've looked at how
在我们研究如何注册之前
to you know to reactive with the
你知道对
database client and mithra reactive
数据库客户端和mithra反应
MongoDB template there are extension
MongoDB模板有扩展
functions like duct flow and dot and and
诸如风管流量和点以及
so on on the reactive mommy-to-be
如此对未来的妈妈
template and other templates as well so
模板以及其他模板
again hopefully none of this is super
再次希望这都不是超级
mood to you it's just that it all blends
对你的心情只是所有的融合
together really nicely in the world of
在一起真的很好
in a world of co-routines in a column I
在第I栏的协同例程世界中
really want to thank you for listening I
我真的很想谢谢你的倾听
hope you got something out of this
希望你从中得到一些东西
obviously we've only just begun right
显然，我们才刚刚开始
the really interesting thing about this
真正有趣的是
is is not what we've done but what we
不是我们所做的，而是我们所做的
can do now right Kotlin co-routines are
现在可以做正确的Kotlin协同例程是
powered our our support for co-routines
支持我们对协同例程的支持
as you can see are powered by these
如您所见，这些功能
reactor types and we're making huge
反应堆类型，我们正在做大
inroads on supporting reactive as much
尽可能多地支持反应式
as possible for all those sort of use
尽可能用于各种用途
cases that makes sense
有道理的案例
I'm excited right I'm excited to see
我很高兴看到我很高兴
what this portends for people that are
这对那些
building applications in Kotlin I talk
我在Kotlin中构建应用程序
to a lot of people that want to use
很多想使用的人
co-routines in Kotlin they're just
他们在科特林的例行公事
shocked when I show them all the support
当我向他们展示所有支持时感到震惊
there's a ton of people who are using
有很多人在使用
Kotlin and they use co-routines in
Kotlin和他们在
android in that case they don't want to
在这种情况下，Android他们不想
block the main thread remember in a UI
阻止主线程记住在UI中
framework like like Android or swing or
像Android或swing或
something like that it's super important
这样的事情非常重要
that your code not languish on the UI
您的代码不会在用户界面上消失
thread you need to get off of that
您需要摆脱的线程
thread so that the the you I can paint
线程，以便您可以绘画
itself as quickly as possible so I can
尽可能快地自己
rerender itself if you sit there waiting
如果您坐在那里等待，请重新显示自己
for data to download things will freeze
用于数据下载的东西将冻结
so having a nice framework like this
所以有这样一个很好的框架
where you can write code that looks like
您可以在其中编写如下代码
it's synchronous
它是同步的
and get the result that you're expecting
并得到您期望的结果
right like in this case I can ask for a
在这种情况下，我可以要求
single record I'm not getting a
单一记录我没有
publisher back I'm just getting a single
发布者回来，我只得到一个
record back and looks like it's working
记录回来，看起来像在工作
that way my code is written in that way
这样我的代码就是这样写的
and I get that sort of determinism I'm
我得到了那种确定性
not worried about like I'm not worried
不用担心我不担心
about you know callback heck you know
关于你知道回调，你知道
going to a callback hell to be able to
去回调地狱，能够
get that so easily and so nicely that's
这么容易，那么好得到的是
a big deal
大不了的
now of course Kotlin support is fairly
现在Kotlin当然支持
new but this idea of of co-routines is
是新的，但是关于协同例程的想法是
not new at all right i I think c-sharp
一点也不新，我认为C锐化
was the first big language to have it
是第一种拥有它的大语言
back in 2012 right so seven years ago
早在2012年，就在七年前
and Python recently got it right Python
和Python最近做对了Python
3 died I don't know seven some of that
3死了，我不知道其中的七个
through that six maybe it was it's a
通过这六个也许是
fairly new thing there async/await
那里相当新的东西async / await
other languages have similar things
其他语言也有类似的东西
right and and I'm just really excited to
对，我真的很兴奋
see what this with this bit this
看看这个与此有什么关系
pretends for us as a community because
为我们装作一个社区，因为
obviously while we're far different from
显然，尽管我们与
an Android use case where a lot of
一个Android用例，其中很多
people are using Kotlin we all know that
人们正在使用Kotlin我们都知道
it's super important that you not block
不要阻塞是非常重要的
you know buck threads on a server
你知道服务器上的buck线程
because threads are expensive they're an
因为线程很昂贵，所以它们
expensive resource so stay tuned my
昂贵的资源，敬请期待
friends and as always thanks so much for
朋友，一如既往地非常感谢
watching
观看
you
您